intro if you're okay. So, uh, here we
are. We're admitting everybody on in
now. Good afternoon, everybody. Uh, my
name is Dominic Zarlo and I am the
center director for medical cannabis and
psilocybin. And so, welcome to this
committee meeting this afternoon. This
is the training and education committee.
And just as a reminder, we do record
these meetings and put them up on the
website. So, please remember to keep
your language appropriate for a public
meeting. Um, and uh, with that, we have
our chair for this meeting is Brenda
Burgard. And I'll turn it on over to
you, Brenda, for uh, your usual
introductions and everything else. And
then when you're ready, I I'm ready to
present.
>> Okay. Well, thank you, Dominic, and
thank you everyone for showing up today.
I'm Brenda Bergard. I'm chairing the
education and training for the medical
psilocybin program. And I also too
wanted to make a little announcement
that I have Katherine Waro and Kate Hawk
also on our little like committee here
to help shape some of the education
parts and training parts because uh a
lot of times people who are in the
training and education part there is so
much information that we want to be able
to get enough
information
in the right way in teaching it. So I I
feel that both of um uh Kate and
Katherine are very competent to help
with um shaping this. So um so uh do we
need to make some introductions here? Um
anybody want to raise their hand and
introduce themselves to the group here?
All right. And as a reminder to raise
your hand, um there is a icon that says
raise with a hand on the top banner on
Teams. Um and then once you do that, we
can enable your mics from there.
All right, I see Ian Dun's hand up and
Ian, you can unmute.
>> Good morning, everyone. My name is Ian.
I'm the chair of the medical psilocybin
advisory board. I'm just here to support
in any way I can. Um, thank you all for
being here and it's good to see you
again, Brenda.
>> It's good to see you too, Ian. And thank
you for coming to the meeting today.
>> All right. And in the chat, we've got
Sky Rivers uh with the Santa Fe reporter
sitting in. Welcome, Sky. And I see Ted
uh Dimmond has his hand up. And Ted, I
have enabled your mic and you can unmute
um up at the mic button.
>> All right, I think I did that. Hi, I'm
Ted Diamond. Um I'm an LPCC and have a
private practice in Tal, New Mexico.
I've been in Tal for just short of 50
years. And I'm very exciting about
what's happening in the state around uh
plant medicine treatment. I'm very
interested in integrating it into my
practice up in Tal and someone had it
alerted to me alerted me that I could
attend a meet this meeting and so I'm
very interested in how all of these um
important and complicated protocols and
decisions are going to be made and as I
said also personally interested because
I hope to be able to find the adequate
train training uh to obtain the
credentiing I would like to have for my
practice. So, thanks for welcoming me
and allowing me to attend this meeting.
>> Thank you, Ted, for um coming to the
meeting today. Yes, this is uh this type
of meeting is especially for um us
therapists to come in and uh learn more
about what this is going to look like,
how things are going to roll out and be
trained. So, thank you for showing up
today for the meeting.
>> Thanks.
>> All right. And next, we've got James
Brown and your mic is enabled. Afternoon
everyone. Again, Brenda, thank you for
sharing this. Uh you look amazing today.
Uh everyone, thank you for being here
and allowing me to have uh opinions and
representation. Um and you know, just
input. Um this is such an amazing
process and something that we really are
going to impact New Mexico with. So,
thank you again and happy Friday.
Thanks, James, for being here today. And
thanks uh uh and I and I want to thank
you especially because you your input in
all of these meetings is is vital. Um
you've uh you know, you've really been
very involved with everything. So, I
really appreciate that.
>> All right. And Katherine Waro is next.
And Katherine, I have enabled your mic.
>> Hello everybody. I'll just chime in real
quick. I'm Katherine Waro, LPCC down in
Los Cusus. Been very active in um as
many of these subcommittees as possible.
Appreciative to everybody that's here.
Um that's it. Thanks.
Thanks, Katherine, for showing up today.
And I wanted and I don't know if anybody
caught that earlier, but um Katherine
and Kate Hawk are both going to help uh
shape some of the training and education
part. And I just wanted to welcome you
again, Katherine, for showing up today.
Thank you.
>> All right. And Kate Hawk is next. And I
have enabled your mic.
>> Hi everybody. Okay. So, I was out of
reach until just a minute ago, but yes,
I'm happy to pitch in however I keep
I've done training for the Colorado
licenses computer training and
maps and back in the day trained couple
thousand trauma therapist.
be interested in training of how we're
going to balance having access and not
not too much training required but
making sure we do get people qualified.
>> Thank you Kate for for being here today
and yes uh Kate is also um going to be
on uh the little committee here that
we're going to um start
creating some um more training and and
education. however that's going to be
panning out. So, thanks Kate.
>> Awesome. Thanks. And then in the chat,
we've got Gregory Evans listening in and
says like Henha Washington from PMHAA is
also in attendance. Uh, all right. Cool.
Cool. And I don't see any more hands up
right now.
>> Okay. So, um, let's give it another
minute or so. Maybe people are still,
um, coming into the room here. Um, and
Chris, um, Puskei is over over here in
the chat, too, and he's a board member.
He's also attending the meeting here.
And, uh, anybody else want to introduce
themselves or say hello or anything like
that?
Okay. Um, Dominic, what do we have
today? Oh, we have Jeff Steinborn. Oh,
wait a minute. Hold on. We got Jeff.
>> All right, there we go.
>> Hey everybody. Hey everybody. Good
afternoon. It's Jeff Steinborn just
listening in. I I love to listen in
while I can, while I'm doing other work
and just so inspired by your work. Thank
you for everything all of you are doing.
Appreciate it so much.
>> Well, we appreciate you, Jeff, very
much. So, oh, do we? We really do. Thank
you for showing up today. Um, okay. So,
Dominic, take it away.
>> Thank you, Brenda. And just uh in the
chat also, Desba did uh let us know that
she is also here today um and is a one
of the board members and actually chairs
the equity and access committee as well.
So um so good afternoon everybody um and
so what we're going to look at today is
we had talked about starting to set up
the different modules and so what we
have done from the program level is we
went through all of the different things
that have been presented so far through
the training and education committee and
we've sort of uh narrowed it on down
into these different areas you know
broadstroke areas of competency and all
of that. Now, when we're talking about
setting up the educational programs and
the organizations that are going to do
it, we don't create an exact curriculum.
We put into the rules and regulations
minimums and categories and that sort of
thing that they'll need to cover. So, as
I go through this, keep that portion in
mind. Um, and um and then we'll talk
about that a little bit. And because we
have the different categories, we do
have different requirements for those
different categories. And when I say
categories, I mean the diagnostic
clinicians who are going to be the
individuals who are um you know
certifying that patients do indeed have
the condition, the qualifying condition
and that uh medical psilocybin would be
an appropriate treatment for them. And
then we have the practitioners who are
really at that therapeutic counselor
type level. and then the facilitators
who are there uh as that presence and
the individuals to be there to help
facilitate the patients through their
journey. Um and so just keep those
aspects in mind. Also realize this is
not a final product and we're here in
part today to hear what things did we
miss? What do we need to add in? Are
they already included in a different
section maybe that got overlooked a
little? And so please do not hesitate as
I go through. The one thing I ask is
I'll go through each section first and
then ask if there's any questions on
that just so that I can sort of keep the
flow going and uh and not um do as I
quite often like to do and get
distracted and go down a total rabbit
hole. So hopefully we can do that. And
Brenda is here to keep me on track. So
uh I think we'll we'll do well.
Uh so let me just share the screen and
just give me a moment. Uh, there we go.
Everybody should be able to see it here
in just a moment if you don't just yet.
And is it large enough print for
everybody?
>> Maybe increase it just a teeny bit more.
>> Absolutely.
There we go. How is that?
>> Oh, perfect. Perfect.
>> Anyone else? Looks good. Okay. See a few
thumbs. All right. So, um, so the first
section I'll start in with is the
diagnostic clinician. And again the role
for the diagnostic clinician is to see
the patient. This is going to be your MD
uh NP uh nurse practitioner um
psychologist uh clinical psychologist
level of individual who is seeing
someone to see whether or not psilocybin
would be appropriate. Quite often this
really can be the patient's primary care
provider. This could be someone that
they've been working with as a
specialist for their condition, that
sort of realm. And so the first part we
have is the New Mexico module. I know in
many of the committees we've talked
about what the department of health is
going to do is create a New Mexico
module. And so what that module consists
of is really a description of what is
the medical psilocybin act, how did we
get here, what some of the timeline is,
differences between state and federal
law, some of the risks like malpractice
and other sort of things around there.
The next step is an overview of
psilocybin therapy in New Mexico. So,
how will the patient flow work? How uh
what do people need to do as far as
emergency response plans? Billing and
coding questions and issues, discussion
about informed consent specifically for
psychedelics, documentation that's going
to be required. So whether it's
registration in the program, data
collection that needs to be done, those
sort of things. And then HIPPA
compliance of course. And this is just a
general overview of HIPPA compliance and
confidentiality.
Any questions on this so far?
>> Pretty tight. Okay.
>> So far. Okay.
>> So then the next step is cultural
competency and sensitivity. So the first
part of that of course is talking a
little bit about equity and access. What
does equity and access mean? Especially
in New Mexico, the history of different
New Mexico cultural considerations. So
here we really look at the different
potential tribal and pblo considerations
the cultures the cultures of what is
what have happened over the last 4 or
500 years how that has influenced some
of the medical and med and uh both
western and non-western med medical
practices and then talking from a
non-western traditional medical models
really going into things such as
language barrier involvement of other
professionals so really looking at
things not just from one specific ific
uh um tradition looking at religious um
religious leaders, deathdas, indigenous
healers, coranderas,
etc. as far as uh how they can be
involved and how they often are involved
in this and then a history of psilocybin
and psychedelic use in New Mexico
specifically. And then really because we
wanted to emphasize that this is a part
of the the the process is really
emphasizing cert which is the spiritual
existential religious and theological
concerns with regard to this. So the
existential and spiritual processing
that people may go through with regard
to psychedelics and so including all of
that on in the New Mexico module and of
course no learning curriculum is
complete without a test. So then there
of course would be a test on the items
within this module. How does this sound
so far?
>> This sounds really
very very nice and concise because th
Yes, we definitely need a test
afterwards and you know that that's the
thing. It's like okay oh my gosh we all
say you know a test but you know I think
it it it will be it it will be um
equitable as well too it the test has to
be um that it's not just from like a
western point of view of testing either
you know those questions have to be
appropriate
>> right correct and that and for this
module and for that test is something
that we'll create from the department of
health we will bring it to everybody so
that you all can, you know, also get a a
preview, but this won't really be
created until a little bit later. So,
give us a few months. We won't have it
next week, but we will have it down the
road here a little bit. And the goal is
for this mo particular module is that
this will be something that everybody
does. So, we've talked in the past about
the reciprocity piece. So, even
individuals who may have been certified
or licensed in the other two states
right now will still need to do this
module. Um and then everybody who is in
New Mexico who wants to be involved will
have to do this module because it gives
this basic broad overview. Um so so with
that I'll sort of move forward a little
bit and so for the diagnostic clinician
um in the next set what they would be
looking at is you know the
pharmarmacological side of it. So what
is psilocybin as a medicine? Are there
interactions with regard to other
medications, supplements, other issues?
How is psilocybin processed in the body?
Doing half-life, all of those sort of
things from a pharmacological
standpoint.
And then looking really at what is the
overview for the diagnostic clinician?
What is their scope of practice? What is
their role within the care team? And I
want to emphasize that aspect because I
think that's a really important one and
it's in all of the different sections
that we have is it's really about nobody
is doing this on their own individually.
It's all a part of a care team. So we
want to make sure that we emphasize that
as part of the training and then the
diagnosis. So what are the current
conditions for the qualifying conditions
for the program and as that changes down
the road adding those on in. But this
would be about what is the diagnosis?
How are the clinicians actually going
about that? Are they ensuring they're
doing it appropriately? And in this
diagnosis, is this something that will
be in this next section? Is it something
that the qualifying conditions will be
beneficial for the patient or more
likely to be beneficial for the patient
than potentially harmful? So doing a
benefit and risk evaluation and then
also looking again as far as medical
evaluation and monitoring um from a
standpoint of kind of setting up a plan
for that. And then the next section is
really about medical monitoring and
emergency situations. That's if for
example say the this particular
diagnostic clinician is part of that
response plan during administration day
and so just as an example if Brenda was
for example guiding uh you know
facilitating and and as a practitioner a
group of people who are going through
has the facilitators there with but
there's a medical emergency and she has
somebody who is an MD or a diagnostic
clinician on call to consult with. So
what does that look like? So what does
medical monitoring for that sort of
situation and emergency response look
like? And then we have a section that we
include in there because um no no
program stays static and especially
psilocybin and psychedelic research is
not static at this time. So we want to
make sure and ensure that there is um a
section that's about research and
evaluation and what's happening what is
moving forward and sort of doing going
forward in that way. Um so okay so at
this point oh and I'm sorry uh Greg you
know that's actually my fault Greg I was
going to copy it and paste it on in as I
was doing it and I got so excited I
forgot. So that's all my my apology.
Sorry if for those who aren't seeing in
the chat. Greg just asked um Jorge to
post it in the chat and that's actually
my fault. I'm the one who forgot that.
So I take ownership. But thank you for
the reminder uh on that Greg. I
appreciate people keeping me on track.
Actually it helps Greg because I
appreciate you're saying that it helps
as I go through to make sure I'm on the
right section and stay on track. So but
thank you. Um so with all of this at
this point so again this is from the
portion on the psilocybin
pharmarmacology the pharmocinetics is
how we have it listed on the page but
going really from there down to again as
we say before it is not a true training
curriculum if there is not a test. So
the very last item down that is the
test. Uh any questions or concerns on
it? Now again, and while I kind of give
people a minute to think about that a
little bit, um remember the diagnostic
clinician for the most part is not going
to be there on the day of. Now, they'd
be welcome to be there, of course,
during the day of someone's journey, but
their position and their role within all
of this is to be there from that medical
sort of standpoint to help refer people
into the program and certify them for
the program. And then to be there really
if there is a medical type of emergency
as part of a initial portion of a
response plan. By the way, not the whole
thing. People should still be calling
911 and all of that. We just want to
ensure that there's that safety aspect
as well.
And so with this, what we really are
looking at is we're keeping this part
for the diagnostic clinician very brief.
You know, we are thinking that the New
Mexico module as we create it will
probably be somewhere in that 6 to 8
hour range. maybe a little more, maybe a
little bit less depending on how uh all
the different parts and pieces fit in.
And then these other portions are really
probably going to be, you know, about
probably another eight uh 8 to 10 hours
total. So this makes it low barrier, low
investment on the part for a diagnostic
clinician, but helps give them a basis
to understand what are they potentially
referring patients into.
And again, those hours may change a
little bit as we start working. And the
other part when we do get to putting
this into final regulation form,
remember that the hours are that we put
in regulation are minima. So that
doesn't mean that an educational program
can't turn around and say, you know
what, we really want to expand on this
particular section, and this is true
through all of this, and we want to add
in an extra segment, an extra portion.
What we're saying here is this will just
be the minimum. So keep that part in
mind. And so when I give you these
approximate times, they really are
approximate, but figure it'll be in
about that range.
>> Absolutely, Dominic. because as as
research is going on and progressing uh
for instance I was reading uh they're
doing studies for Alzheimer's and so and
they're seeing really great results with
that too but it's a small study and by
the time uh we're we're done here and
we're ready to roll there may be more
and more studies coming out so uh this
is um uh really good to have just the
the minimum here but like you said, if
the curriculum needs to be added on to
expand our information and our
education, it'll be there. Thank you.
>> Great.
Okay, I'm not seeing other questions or
concerns, so I will move forward. Um,
now again, we have the New Mexico module
is in each section. So, this next part
is really just for the practitioner. And
so, I will give me just a moment to put
it on in. Um and I'm uh I'm going to do
this by module. So um the first module
that we have uh outside the New Mexico
module um is uh the basic module for
practitioners. Now one of the things as
we've been talking with different things
is requiring that everybody have done a
basic life support certification
um just so that they're ready and able
uh to respond in in the event it is
needed. Um, now that doesn't mean that
the educational program itself has to
offer it. They just need to ensure that
their students have that BLS
certification. So, for example, if you
already have one, um, you know, then you
wouldn't necessarily need to repeat it.
You'll just need to make sure you keep
it current while you're uh a part of the
program. And the same with HIPPA
certification. Um, so there's lots of
information, lots of programs about
HIPPA on out there. program could
actually have their own or they could
utilize one of the existing ones. But we
want to ensure that anybody who is
involved in this has that certification.
And then as we did with um with the
diagnostic um clinician, there is an
overview of the responsibilities for
that practitioner. So their scope of
practice, what their role is within the
care team, their therapeutic
responsibilities, and then a little bit
about research and evaluation. Um, and
this is really basic. So, this is just
very beginnings providing some research
or uh a review of current research,
talking a little bit about research, uh,
how people find it, how they read it,
evaluate it, and really just having a
little section in there about it within
this basic module. And this is really at
a 101 type level. So, if you think about
that aspect and then of course again a
test. So, I think that'll probably be
the most common word I use this
afternoon is a test. So, does this make
sense so far?
>> Absolutely it does. Now, when you're
referring to test, um this is uh this is
part of the the the bigger test. Is that
correct? Um and these will be sections
or
>> so if we look at things from an
educational standpoint, you don't ever
want to test people just once. And so by
doing it in each module, we break that
on up. So it becomes a lot easier for
the individual who is going through the
training to actually be evaluated from a
at a testing level and to be able to see
are there areas they need to improve,
they need to work on rather than trying,
you know, going through all of the
curriculum and then doing just a big
test at the end.
>> Doing it that way makes it very high
stakes, makes it very difficult. And so
we really recommend from an educational
standpoint that you do smaller tests so
you have smaller bites so to speak as
you're going through it. And so this
test would be a test for this module and
so it would include questions for that.
>> Yeah, I like that much better. Yes,
because then then you're not saturated
with a whole bunch of information and
you know your brain just gets overloaded
and then by by the time you're done
you're not
>> if you're anything like me, I have
extreme test anxiety. So, this makes it
a lot easier to digest while you're
going through the test.
>> And if it makes it easier for people to
think about it, you could think about it
as test and evaluation or quiz and
evaluation. Really, whatever terminology
works best for individuals. We really
are talking about this is going to be
that evaluation for the student for that
module. And you'll see it for each
module.
Okay. And I do see we have a couple of
hands on up. So, um I will go uh Chris,
it looks like you're first on that.
>> Hi, Dominic. I just have one
uh I guess recommendation. So, I just
took my BLS certification for my
Colorado license and they focus, you
know, it's primarily focused on CPR. Um,
and specifically with BVMs and unless
we're going to require that equipment in
the classroom, I think a regular CPR
class might be more appropriate. Um,
and then also I might recommend first
aid uh as well because you know people
might cut themselves or injure
themselves in other ways. Um, so those
would be my recommendations on that.
>> Okay, great. Thank you, Chris. I'm
adding them on in. Um, just to note like
some of this does get repeated on um
some of the other sections, but we'll
see about adding it in. Um and um we've
had we have actually had different
people suggest whether you to do BLS or
to do CPR. So that's definitely um you
know a a consideration. So thank you. I
appreciate it.
Okay. And next we have uh Katherine
Waraugh.
>> Yes. I think pharmacocinetics is
important for the practitioner as well.
Um, especially if they're going to be
dosing, they're going to be responsible
for establishing. Oh, it's down there. I
see that. Sorry, it is. Okay. No, that's
okay, Katherine. I would rather you you
jump ahead than miss us miss something.
So, you are perfectly fine.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> No, thank you, James.
>> Dominican group, you know, my thought on
the competency test. I love the the the
breaking down of the individual groups.
Great idea. Can you expand a little bit
on on and let us know what kind of test
is that going to be? Is that going to be
a multiplechoice test? And then or or
fill in the blanks, you know, is there
going to be sections and thoughts on
that? And then also, is there going to
be um with these competencies, you know,
a lot of these times where you have
individuals take the test multiple
times, let's say, you know, heaven's
sake, they don't pass and they take it.
Is it really going to be enforcing the
material or just a way to get through
that test? You know, like where you
retake it and you're like, "Okay, I put
A, B, and I put B last time. I I need
I'm gonna try C, you know, and so I just
I just thoughts on tests. That's all."
Thank you.
>> Yeah. So, thank you, James. That's a
really good point. Now, we're not
necessarily going to put that specific
like like a requirement of what exactly
type of test needs to be uh for the
different sections. And for some of
them, you know, some multiple choice
might be perfectly acceptable,
but what the tests are really going to
need to do is evaluate people's
competency in that area. And so, even
for each of these modules, are they have
they actually learned the material? We
don't want people teaching to the test.
And so, as we go through and do that, it
really should be more interactive. Um
and and so hopefully we will see that
but we will from a department standpoint
we will be evaluating the curriculum as
the programs submitted and if they're
not demonstrating that the exams that
they'll use partic in their because
their curriculums will vary somewhat if
they are not showing that their exams
actually are demonstrating knowledge and
understanding of the material then
they're going to have to go back to the
drawing board on that um and um without
getting into because I could talk for
hours just about evaluation techniques
and how that happens. Um, you know, but
they're going they are going to need to
do that and some may be a little bit of
multiple choice, but most of it is going
to be really being able to demonstrate
the ability to do it. And the curricula
or the different organizations could set
it up where part of it being oral, part
of it being demonstration, some of it
being written. And so doing that in a
variety of ways and not doing it in just
one. So that exact we do miss out or we
do avoid that whole situation of oh
here's a multiplechoice test and I'm
just going to keep taking it until I get
the order of letters correct. I hope
that helps.
Okay, thumbs up. Thank you. Okay, and
next uh Chris back to Chris.
>> Uh just one more thought on the BLS. Um,
we might consider doing a wilderness
first aid for people that are having
journeys more than an hour away from
um, medical support.
Might be a good idea to have a little
bit higher requirement if you don't have
med uh, EMS available within an hour
given our rural state conditions.
>> Right. Thank you, Chris. Um, yeah, that
is a possibility. that would be
something that might fit in to one of
the categories a little later, but I've
put it here denote so that I do not
forget about that.
So, thank you. And Greg, you're next.
>> Hey, good afternoon. Um, I think a
hierarch like but just on what Chris was
talking about hierarch hierarchial like
super
position where like woofer would absorb
first aid and CPR, first aid would
absorb CPR, that sort of thing like
could be a way to handle all that. Um
and but what I wanted to mention is
that it seems really important to
understand that the department of health
is here is designing the frameworks. The
individual facilities, the private
businesses that are running training and
education get to decide how they decide
that these needs are being met that are
specified by the department. So like
Dominic, as much as you could probably
run an education center, I see your
restraint in defining how these
companies and businesses decide to do
things. I do want to point out that I
very much appreciate the research
evaluation section here in the guidance
for the fact that this is all emerging
research and by tomorrow things could
easily change in our understanding.
having the capacity to continue learning
and not not just that but like defining
that like you the these practitioners
understand it's their responsibility to
continue learning and develop and com
and contribute to the field anyways um
just
moving on
>> okay thank you Greg I appreciate it uh
and next we have Ian Ian go ahead
>> hi um yeah I just wanted to similarly
reiterate. It's just we're kind of
setting the minimum competencies and
then anything above that like they're
more than welcome to do. Um and in fact
even if this committee wanted to once we
get this the ground level down the
committee could make guidance and go
into what they would like to see in
programs. Not saying that people have to
adhere, but um if that's something that
the committee would like to discuss more
cuz I don't want to just dismiss them,
but two, we do need to get through like
the the minimum first and then we can
talk about, you know, um the creative
side where we get to express, you know,
the what we would ideally like each
program to look like. Um anyway, thank
you.
>> No, Ian, that's a great point. Just like
with regard to for example an
administration day where we've talked
about best practices. So things that
aren't necessarily a part of the reg the
regulations but are best practices.
There's very similar processes within
education where you know you have your
different benchmarks and objectives and
best practices. And so those are some
things that we also can provide and this
committee down the road can also work on
as far as doing that. So that's a great
point.
Okay,
any other comments at this point?
Okay, I'll move on to the next module.
Um, so this one is uh the what we've
called the psilocybin therapeutic
module.
Um and on this one it's really about
talking specifically about the
psilocybin phbo pharmarmacinetics and
the pharmarmacology talking in general
about the session and dosing experience
and I say in general because there's
going to be a little more cure coming up
in the next module on that and then
really um looking at a review of
education of psychedelic therapeutic
model modalities. So talking again in
more depth than just what the New Mexico
module would have done but about the
history of psilocybin use different
models of psilocybin treatment that
there are talking about cultural
humidity humility uh patient autonomy
non-ordinary states of consciousness
ethics power dynamics touch so
supportive touch consent about that
nondirective approach and traumainformed
care
I know that's a mouthful that going
through that whole this. Um, and then we
really wanted to pull out and emphasize
a little bit about individual treatment
modalities and group treatment
modalities and dynamics since this could
be potentially in either of those types
of settings. And then psychedelic
deescalation techniques. And then of
course it's been very clear in many of
these that we also need to ensure that
there is uh a portion about self-care.
And so that for the practitioners
themselves on on that
Oh, Katherine. Uh, cultural, I'm sorry,
cultural and spiritual. Absolutely, we
can add that.
So, any thoughts, comments?
Okay. Well, with that, I'll move to the
next set. Uh, and so which is set and
setting. Um,
and so let me put it in the chat. There
we go. Uh, and so set and setting is
really going to be it's about the the
room, the building, the therapy space.
Is it is it an appropriate space? Um,
what has happened with regard to that?
Have you created that space? And those
discussions that quite often happen
about how do you create a therapeutic
space? Um and then the preparation
settings talking about how to
communicate with patients about their
therapeutic goals and aims, how to
explain psychedelic experiences for
patients, and again of course
trauma-informed care. Um administration
day itself looking at medication use,
the different potential therapy
modalities, um and then emergency
preparedness. So this is a part that uh
Chris I was thinking this would we might
be where a specific portion on somebody
getting the wilderness training first
aid training and all that might go for
those who are looking at doing it
because that would really be a part of
what kind of setting are they sort of
setting up um and um uh James it does
include that as far as power dynamics
does include personal bias that's always
a part of power dynamics I think um but
maybe that's just to me and that may be
something we need to put in uh in
writing itself. Um and then um to
continue on integrative sessions. So
this is your post admin administration
and really what continues on for those
weeks and months later is the different
models of therapy that are appropriate
for psilocybin treatment and after care
and trauma informed care of course
continuing on with that. Um and then the
other portion within here is the medical
monitoring during sessions. What needs
to happen? what should occur, what is
needed in order to be able to do that.
What are their plans for the next
section on if there happens to be an
emergency or an emergency or something
that happens, not necessarily even just
psychedelic, it could be something else.
For example, someone could get nauseous,
they are being assisted to the bathroom,
they slip, they fall, something anything
in particular that could happen outside
of the norm. And so does the you know
how do you set up safety protocols and
ensure that you have those? And then of
course as I keep saying a test
any thoughts or ideas?
>> Um I have a thought. I have a thought.
>> Yeah, go for it. Um I think um with a
lot of the training um and um that you
know especially when we get to the point
for practicum and everything I think
role play is really really important
and that gives you really the hands-on
kind of experience that you need as a
practitioner co-f facilitator to
understand exactly what that looks like
because you can read something and you
go, "Well, oh, okay, I got it." But then
you don't really know how it presents
itself in reality. So, it may look good
on paper, but when we really get into
the nitty-gritty of of someone who is
being really reactive to something and
going through a very stressful,
traumatic part of their um uh their
journey, then we we know what we can say
or do or not do in those in those
instances. So, it's um I know from my
own training
uh doing crisis training at Agora for
sui suicide um risk assessments that
that's really important to do that role
playing because everybody's going to be
doing presenting differently and some
people are more tolerant with uh adverse
uh uh experiences in um you know a
psilocybin
experience.
uh others uh for instance if they've
never had the experience before um I
think this is where the preparation part
of it is also really important for the
for a client but going back to the the
role playinging I think uh knowing how
to present role playinging in a teaching
um curriculum would be um a vital part
for this as well
>> and Brenda I completely completely agree
and I think within the different modules
they the the educators really should be
utilizing role play but to ensure that
we do have that the very next module is
actually simulated patients um which of
course is a type of role play but it
could include other role plays as well
because you're right that is absolutely
important and we do not want anyone
starting to do this work especially you
know the therapeutic side without having
gone through some of that simulated
patient module. And so what I'll
actually do is this next section, two
sections really. Um, but we're not going
to cover the practicum portion just yet.
Um, but the next two parts are the
simulated patient module and then the
practicum requirements. And so we do
have both of those for these. And we're
going to get into the practicum after we
review through facilitator just so that
we do the curriculum side first and then
we'll talk about practicum just so
everyone knows. Uh, and then I do see
James has hand up. And uh, before James,
before you do it, Katherine, again, not
a problem. Go ahead and be be ahead.
That's perfectly fine. Again, I would
much rather uh, somebody catch something
that we missed rather than us miss it
just because it's in a later section.
So, James, go ahead.
>> Dominic, you know, I want to give you
guys kudos for the therapy modality
edition. I really, really appreciate
that. um under that administration day,
you know, those other modalities are so
key and important to the total
experience um you know and and opening
that container. Um and I think that that
um is something that we can
individualize and and these programs can
really dial up. But is there some other
things that you think with the
modalities? What was your thoughts on
the types of modalities? Are we just
going to kind of leave it open or is
there going to be more u specifics? Just
thoughts.
Yeah, I I think that right now we would
leave it open. Again, from a regulatory
standpoint, you don't want to start
listing in all the different potential
modalities because there's hundreds of
them, quite frankly. Um, and so it
really is going to be up to the programs
to make some of that determination. Um
and also what this allows is as there is
additional research as we learn more
about psilocybin therapy and psychedelic
therapy and more more generally this is
the kind of thing that can be adapted a
lot more readily um through that
educational curriculum because we are
going to require review of curriculum
over time.
Uh, and Katherine, that's a great point.
And that's actually a part of the uh
when the programs, sorry everyone, I'm
jumping ahead a little bit in the chat.
Katherine asked, uh, I think we should
make sure no one delivers a modality
they're not trained in. That will be a
part of the application process for the,
uh, the program. So, great thought. Uh,
we definitely think alike on that. And
then, uh, Senator Steinborn has actually
said uh, and welcome Senator Steinborn,
there are newish, uh, virtual trainings
and simulation apps. How do we feel
about the role of those? It seems a
great way for facilitators to get a lot
of practice in real world real world
simulations. And yes, that definitely is
something that um that these training
programs can actually utilize um and
something that others can. There's been
a couple that we actually have also been
granted access to and have gone through
to see how they're set up. Sometimes
they can be very clunky, sometimes they
can be very smooth. Um but they
definitely are a great place where
people can get some experience uh with
regard to this. So
>> yeah and let me mention that they need
to be approved by the deal too.
>> Right. Right. Remember all of this is
contingent upon the organizations
essentially sitting in submitting an
application that says we agree to abide
by these uh these general guidelines or
these regulations and here is what our
curriculum is. They will have to hand us
and turn over to us the curriculum for
evaluation. We also are going to be
putting in that they'll need to do and
have a third party evaluation. I think
I've said many times on several of the
uh different committees where one of the
biggest areas where where um different
programs are lacking is that they don't
actually have a curricula evaluation
report and that's something that's very
important to ensure that they are doing
things appropriately correctly in
training others. Um, and one of those,
by the way, Katherine, uh, just to sort
of emphasize on it would be, are the
people who are training, are they in
themselves experts?
Is this all making sense? And James,
your hand is still up. I just want to
make sure. Is that up again or is that a
just carryover?
Okay, just carry over. Okay.
Okay. Any other thoughts, questions so
far?
Okay. So, uh the next step is
facilitator. And as I mentioned before
with some of those other changes and
additions like uh as Chris had brought
up as far as CPR and all that, I I
haven't made it in here. So, it's still
in here uh the way it was before. We'll
make those adjustments as we of course
move forward. Um but um for
facilitators, so we'll start out with
the basic module. Now, you'll look and
see this is very familiar. looks very
much like the other uh like the
practitioner. But what one of the things
that we also added was essentially a 101
type overview for therapeutic practices
because facilitators are not going to be
individuals who while many of them may
have lenture in other areas, they may
not have lenture. And so we want to
ensure that they have at least a base
understanding of therapeutic practices
before they go into the other portions
of the curriculum. And so we did include
here in the basic module that they would
also need to go through this overview of
therapeutic practices. Other than that,
this basic module to start is pretty
much the same, but it does should cover
things like ethics, confidentiality,
therapeutic modalities, not necessarily
just with regard to um uh psilocybin and
psychedelics, but just in general so
that they have a good basis for that. Is
that making sense? I hope. Any questions
so far?
James, go for it.
>> Dominic, what about adding that power
dynamics to this because that personal
bias is really big in that you know that
facilitator role
>> that's down here.
>> You're you're good, James. Uh but that's
a part of this next section. So um are
there other comments or thoughts with
regard to that?
Nope. Okay. So I will put it the next
section. So again you'll notice this is
very much similar. What we really see
again is the facilitators still need to
go through these same sort of trainings.
And what we really see is what the big
difference is going to be is that
facilitators may be coming at this from
a more naive or a a situation where they
don't have as much background. And so
they just may need a little bit more of
that 101 and a little bit more of that
support. And that will be up to the the
organizations, the companies that set up
the education to be able to help and
provide that support.
Is that making sense?
Oh, and James, thank you. Since I'm
right here on this page, let me add that
on in.
Oh, okay.
Okay. And then the next part is going to
be again very similar. It's about the
set and settings.
Um and again in this case they're really
going to need to go through the same
kind of training. Again the difference
is going to really be a little bit in
intensity. So they would have some
additional hours but really talking
about how to communicate with patients.
Um because the facilitators while they
may and we've talked about this before
in several of the committees be involved
in some of the preparatory sessions and
be doing some of that aspect and in some
of the postadministration integrative
sessions. you know, they're going to be
there and they quite often they'll be
present, but the primary person for
those really is going to be that
practitioner at that therapeutic level.
But we do want to ensure that they are
involved in this uh to different degrees
and that's actually going to be a part
of the training we mentioned earlier um
up above uh as far as what their scope
of practice and what their role is
within the care team in that basic
module for facilitators. So for
facilitators that basic module is going
to be a lot longer um than these other
areas necessarily. I hope that makes
sense
>> James.
>> Sorry it's me again. Sorry D.
>> Don't be sorry I make great suggestions.
Do not be sorry
>> on administration day. Oh thank you sir.
Um I really think there needs to be a
transportation piece here. I think as a
facilitator, you really need to own some
on that administration day a
transportation element of of you know,
how's this person going to transition
home? How's this person going to do that
stuff? I just think it's important. I
just see it missing. That's all. Thank
you.
>> No, that's a great thought. Thank you,
James.
Um, one thing I else I want to add to
that is is we need to know that also uh
when when they are done with their
session that they're going back to a
safe place and that, you know, there's
an additional um check-in, you know,
within like the following day to follow
up on on a um a client that uh may not
have a really great um environment to go
back into. So um you know I think this
is something that we could um also
discuss further on down the road. this
is totally different separate type of
situation but um I think having
something where maybe even if people
don't have a safe place to go that maybe
there could be something where where
they could go um for at least 24 hours
in order to get acclimated back into
their uh their normal lives because
sometimes you know maybe uh they're
they're caring for an elderly
parent and it it then they have to kind
of switch gears and they're not ready
yet to go back. So maybe having
something else in place there for uh uh
afterare.
>> You know, Brenda, I think that's a
really good point and part of that is
also uh really also falls somewhat into
uh the requirements um that we've talked
about uh in some of the other committees
as far as for what happens on dosing day
on administration day and what the
facility itself. So the location needs
to ensure that they have in place like
do they have those plans to ensure
whether it be the therapist or you know
the facilitator but somebody there is
ensuring they have a safe place to go to
do they have a plan and I think
transportation is a part of that but
having that and including it in as part
of the discussions during the curriculum
I think is very important. So yeah thank
you uh Greg.
Hey, I'm still trying to map out the
specifics of what I was trying to say.
But what it seems like you could do here
under administration day is uh bucket
everything under some categories like so
you have practical logistics and those
practical logistics are going to contain
this and that like how do we touch these
points and then the dosage logistics and
there's a bunch of details under that
and then the modalities that we planned
and are we in line with the plan that
we've created and then also that exit
plan of how this integrates into the
rest of of the integration plan. Um, but
then like all of the emergency
preparedness, all of the preparations
for challenging experiences,
identifying what is an adverse and
experience and how we handle those
things can all be under that other
bucket. So look, to me it looks like
four maybe five buckets with lots of
details inside.
>> Right. And and you've got that just
right, Greg. And in addition to that,
this is also a part some of these things
we're talking about right now as far as
for safety for them. That also fits in
in under the safety protocol, you know.
So, just for example, uh if we have
somebody who has been drinking or using
another substance, we don't want them
driving. That needs to be a part of the
discussion. We definitely don't want
someone who's gone through their journey
to suddenly go and get in a car and
drive somewhere. Um and so those are a
part of it. And um you know and I think
that's a part of that that next section
down a little further about those safety
protocols. But remember when we're
training and educating people while we
like to think about things being all in
very different sections there is a lot
of overlap in different categories and
areas. So what we're really saying is
we're saying here are the main
categories and areas that need to be
covered. And as you cover them, you
might cover something a little bit
differently or a little in a different
way or based upon the reactions of the
class. You know, as a teacher, I may put
a have a set of PowerPoints and have
slides, but based upon how the students
in the class are learning, I may shift
things around a little bit so that I'm
actually taking advantage of the areas
that they're doing well in or focusing
even a little more on the areas where
they may be struggling. And so just
remember those sort of things too. This
is that generalized overview and uh
definitely those different areas are
things people can add on in or the
training programs can add on in. Um and
they might do it in a slightly different
way. We want to make sure they're
covering it overall.
Any other thoughts or ideas?
Okay. And so then again, and I haven't
put it up in there, uh, the next set of
course is that the individuals go
through, uh, the simulated patients and
the practicum requirements. And so, uh,
now I know that's the part everybody
wants to see, right? It's all about
practicum. So, I've already mentioned
and I've got it up on screen. Um, this
one's a little more dense and it's just
simply because I was working on it
separately. Um and and by the way, I I
do want to also give a big shout out to
our entire team here. Um and not just uh
both people who have been involved in
all of these meetings because that's
where we have distilled all of this
from. We went through took all of the
different documents, the ones Brenda has
done, Katherine, other people have
submitted um and we've taken them and we
really distilled it on down into what
are these major categories and areas.
How will this look? And so it's really
been that and I really want to give big
kudos to our team on the medical
psilocybin program. They've been working
on this very diligently and going
through and if you only knew how many
times I've turned around and said, "Wait
a minute. Didn't we already do that
yesterday?" and realized that it was all
in my head. So, um you know, but they
really have been phenomenal in us going
through it. Um and putting up with me,
by the way, is probably the most
difficult thing they have to do. So, um
so here, let me put this on up. And
again, I'm going to do this a little bit
in se sections. And you'll see they are
separated a little bit um as far as uh
certain areas of them. And again,
remember we've done this and we've put
these hours in. They can potentially be
adjusted, but we do want to hear what
people think. And part of what this
comes the this timing, the number of
hours and all of that comes from is
different people suggesting and making
different thoughts and ideas and us
focusing on the fact that we want to
ensure people have practiced before we
uh unleash them upon patients so to
speak.
We want to make sure that people are
comfortable and when we go and we look
at things like internships or supervised
practicums in various fields and in
different areas it quite often I mean
for the amount that we have here it's
very minimal compared to many of the
others. So, for example, if um if
someone wants to become uh and and do a
licensed clinical social worker, um oh,
now I forgot. I had it I pulled it up
earlier, but they have to do something.
It's is it Brenda, do you recall? Is it
a thousand or 2,000 hours supervised? I
think it's 2,000.
>> Um I think with um Well, I think it is
actually
3,000
uh a thousand hours. um you're you get
with um you're doing your master's
program and then the other two hours is
you're getting that after you graduate
and you're keeping track of your
supervision hours,
>> right? And I know for me if for example
with with my particular lensure in
educational psychology um like just to
be a school counselor for example, I'd
have to do 2,000 hours of a supervised
internship or practicum. And so we
really thought as we were talking about
this and different people bringing in um
different folks and I know Katherine I
don't want you to feel like you were you
were being uh called out on it because
you had talked in one meeting I I did
ask you point blank how many patients
you think you're not the only person
I've asked. I've asked a whole bunch of
people and everybody almost everybody
was in that same range. So, we really
talked about how much time does that
really include and so that's where we
came up with this idea and what I'm I'm
just going to kind of bullet point it
where what we really do is the
facilitators would have 100 hours of
supervised practice and then
practitioners have 120 hours. And so
what this would be is that they all
students would have to participate in a
minimum of 80 hours of the
administration and same day therapy
sessions. So we've talked about what
those are um and that they would need to
do that. We did put in a minimum of 14
different patients with different eight
different administration sessions. Now
the reason we did that is we wanted to
ensure that people are familiar with
both of those major types individual and
group. And so we did six different
patients during six different
administration sessions and then two
groups with at least four or more
patients as well. And so when we really
started to figure out how much time does
that really mean taking into account
when people are setting up after you
know discussions after the day because
part of this should include whoever the
supervising practitioner is discussing
with the students what do you think how
did the day go what occurred what could
we have done better what could have you
know potentially happened otherwise you
know going through all of that we
realize that if we're talking about this
That's really about a 100 or 80 hours
total for those administration sessions.
So figuring about 10 hours for each
administration day.
Um and then does that make sense by the
way so far before I just jump into the
next thing?
Yeah. Okay. Uh and then the next part
would be 20 hours of in-person
preparation and post-integration therapy
sessions where students are able to
again experience what allows during the
preparatory and the post integrative
therapy sessions. And again here we set
a minimum of six different patients in
individual sessions and one group uh
with a minimum again of four patients.
And the group has to be, and it doesn't
have to be the same group, but one group
for the preparatory and one group for
the post.
Okay, is that all making sense so far?
Oh, did I miss and did I move forward on
that, Jorge? I did. Sorry. My apologies
everyone. Uh I I of course started I did
what I tried not to do and I jumped
ahead a little bit. So, thank you for
posting it, Jorge. Yeah. Y
>> yeah. Uh okay. And James, you have your
hand up. Go ahead.
Hey Dominic, just one question on um
because of New Mexico and because of the
ruralness and because of access for this
and and the min like what I'm talking
about is there's minimally trained
individuals out there right now and some
of this stuff with my question is that
that minimal number on the group
sessions where you're talking about four
I just think that's a little aggressive
when you have to have four people in a
group uh for that requirement. That's
all where it says a minimum of two.
That's great. Different sessions with
the group at the same time with four
individuals in each. I just feel like
that's going to be kind of hard to fill.
Um I just thought that might need to be
a little bit less than four personally,
but I just and you know just thought
>> so so remember um so the thing the big
thing is is it's four patients. So I
don't think that really is going to be
an issue so much. And yes, there may be
with regard to some of the more rural
areas that potentially could be an
issue, but I think that there will be
enough people who are doing who are
engaging in this practice and engaging
in the program that being able to do
that in group sessions is going to be I
I don't think that's going to be a
burden on that. Um and and the thing to
also note is you may realize that we
have said in here that one of the things
that we've had in this is that these are
all in person. We don't want to
discourage people from doing things down
the road potentially virtually. We've
talked about some of that where some of
the sessions and some of the things can
have virtual components but for people
to really get the practice to really get
that understanding.
It's come clear in several of the
different committee meetings that it
really needs to be done in person for
the practicum side. Um, and moving
forward on that afterwards, you know, if
people want to do additional or for
example, if a curriculum program says we
would like to also offer uh an
additional set so that people can really
see what virtual looks like, absolutely
fine. But for the for the purposes of
doing this, we really looked at this.
And by the way, we did have some people
who said that the groups should be at
least six or eight. And so the four is
actually sort of a compromise. And I
think Katherine, thank you. I think you
just put in there that yes, part of the
reason for the four is that group
dynamic is really being able to show
that. Um, but I do understand your
concern, James. I just think that
especially when we're getting people
trained up and we're we're teaching
them, sometimes we are going to need to
do things that are going to be a little
bit more uh
aggressive isn't the word I would
choose, but I think we need to be in
that category. You know, that we need to
ensure that that's happening. Um, but
again, open for comment on it. Greg,
you've got your hand up.
>> I think the word you're looking for is
thorough.
>> Thorough. Thank you. Very good. Thank
you. I appreciate it. Good.
>> And I appreciate the thorosity. It's a
word. I made it up. Um I'm wondering if
there is like potential for uh forked
pathways for
um say I'm an individual that wants to
go through a course of study that ends
in a practicum and I come out with
a certification to do one-on-one and
then I want there's another person that
wants to just do group therapy and then
there's another type of person that
wants to be certified in both and have
that as a part of their practice.
Do you think that there's a forked path
or is it better to just make sure
everybody kind of like gets a broader
general experience? So that's a great
question and uh you know there's
actually different parts where we could
potentially do that sort of thing but
remember also this is really a minimum
and so when we're looking at this from a
minimum we want to ensure that people
actually know and they have some
experience across some of these
different areas. Um you know one of the
things we even uh had considered was
saying that uh even during the practicum
there must be you know different
supervising
practitioners so that the students
actually get a wide variety of how do
practitioners themselves know therapists
themselves set things on up but that
becomes very complex. So while that may
go into a best practice, not so much
into the regulatory side, the regulation
itself, but I think that it's important
for people to know and at least
experience that difference between
individual and group because you might
otherwise have someone who thinks, oh, I
only want to do individual therapy and
then they go to one group and they go,
"Wow, I actually really enjoy doing the
group and I feel better on that." So we
want to make sure they at least have
that experience. Um, if we were doing
something where there was, for example,
a more advanced practicum where someone
individualizes a little bit more, I
think that's where that part would come
in. Um, so great thoughts and great
ideas, but I think we want to make sure
this is that base education, so to
speak. I hope that makes sense.
>> Love it. Thank you.
>> Okay, perfect. Um, okay. And then the
other part that we also have is you know
for the practitioners since they will
essentially be supervising facilitators
you know and doing all of that the next
addition really is that practitioners do
have that additional 20 hours. So on the
if you look at the a little bit earlier
it said 100 for facilitators and 120 for
practitioners. And so the additional 20
for the practitioners is where they then
are acting as that practitioner for the
entire room with a supervisor who
essentially is there just in case there
are issues, concerns and for them to
rely on. And so for this with that 20
hours, we do have two different patients
and one group uh on that.
Um does this all make sense?
seeing thumbs up and all of that. Uh
okay. And so uh the other parts that we
have included on this is that all of
these must take place in an approved
healing center. Please remember however
a healing center that is just the term
for an approved location. Um and so uh
uh you know this could be something that
as we go into the discussions of how can
this be done safely in an outdoor
setting and all of that, it can be in
those locations. um don't think of a
healing center as just primarily brick
and mortar. So we just wanted to make
sure that everybody knew that these
would take place. The location it
happens has to be an approved center or
approved location. Um and then of course
just the note that all of the
supervisors and students during
practicums will have to follow all the
rules, regulations and best practices
with regard to facilitation and practice
but not limited to the standards for
confidentiality and the limits on their
scope of practice.
Oh and yes we do have that in the chat.
Okay. So now the next step and this is
something that especially as we've
talked with people in the other states
that are doing this is one of the things
that's come up very clearly is well what
happens after somebody graduates and now
they're off on their own and they're
doing their working on their own
practice and doing all of that. So one
of the things that came up was a
mentoring requirement. And so what we
thought is we would add in a mentoring
requirement for this where all of the
educational programs would have to
provide their students with 10 hours
minimum of mentoring sessions after
graduation and practicum is complete.
And so of course the purpose of this is
to ensure that those graduates have
somebody who they can consult with and
they can ask questions and they can you
know refer and talk about how did they
work through those question through
those issues or concerns on their own
and what are other potential ways that
that may happen. And we have we will
indicate that these are not an
additional charge beyond the cost of the
educational program itself. um and that
they are only valid for up to 12 months
after graduation and practicum is
complete and if students do want more
than that that will be between them and
the educational program and there may be
an additional cost. Now the reasons we
did that is because of course the cost
of all of this is always been paramount
for everybody who has been involved. So
we wanted to make sure that this was
built into here is a part of your
program is that you are also just like
we do with patients that there's
afterare this we have after graduation
mentoring and so really sort of that
same type of situation and the main
reason why we did have that the 10 hours
are valid up to 12 months is we don't
want to have a situation where three
years later somebody turns around and
goes Brenda I need you to I still have
two hours left and I want to consult
with you. I mean, you could still do
that, but that would then be at whatever
that individual had set up for
consultations.
What do people think about this? Does
this sound reasonable? Does this sound
good? Is this something that people can
get behind? Uh, Greg, go ahead. You've
got your hand up.
>> I think this is awesome.
Um, and I'm gonna ask, and I know it's
below the fold, do we have continuing
education requirements included in this
as well?
>> We do,
but that's perfectly fine.
>> We'll get there. We'll get there. We'll
get there.
>> We'll get there. Yes. Uh, Katherine.
>> Yeah. Um, so I guess I'm just wondering
about this no additional charges. So,
does that mean that the educational
program has to offer each student 10
hours at no charge? Is that what you're
saying?
>> We're saying it has to be built into the
cost of the curriculum.
>> So, can you offer different curriculum
for facilitators versus practitioners?
>> Well, it'll be based upon what we have
uh here in the outline. Um, so they'll
be very they they're basically very
similar, but for facilitators there is
that 101 additional aspects to it.
>> So they would be different. Okay, that
makes more sense. Okay. And then I asked
a question. I don't know if it's
relevant, but are there going to be
healing centers that are um accepted
before approved before the end of the
year or Oh, yes. Does Okay. Okay.
>> Yeah. So that
>> No, no. Oh, I'm sorry, Katherine. I
didn't mean to cut you off. I'm excited.
Can you tell I'm excited?
>> Yes, that's exciting.
>> So, my apologies on that.
>> No worries.
>> Um, but yes, so so what we're doing from
the regulatory standpoint is um we
should have the the testing and
cultivation here very shortly. Um, and
then the next step as far as being uh
finalized, promulgated um and so in
effect. This next step is the these
educational which we've said we want to
have in place uh or we want to start for
that rule making process so that where
we have to publish and do the 30 days
and then do the rule hearing all of that
here by the end of July and we're
actually very well on track for that. So
I have no doubt that we're going to hit
that that mark and then the next step is
actually um the approved location rule
along with um equity and access. So
looking at the equity fund, how that
gets dispersed, who's eligible, etc.,
that sort of thing. And that part we're
looking at September to try to have that
done. So that's going to happen really
over the just the next few months. I
know it's very fast.
>> Yeah, that's amazing. So healing
centers. So even if we're delayed, we're
looking at October, maybe November, but
but it will happen before so that people
can get trained. But here's my next
question then. So, we probably can't
like bring clients into the mix until
because they all have to have a di is
that going to also be allowed sooner or
are we going to have to practice on each
other? I guess I'm just curious about
that. So the idea behind it is that and
part of the reason why we have this
particular flow is that the rules here
for training and education once they're
approved we're only going to be about a
month or two behind that for the healing
centers and because the healing centers
you know the thing to remember is that's
not going to be a very difficult
prospect on it. What we're really going
to be looking at quite frankly is are
the locations people looking at safe?
>> Have you done the things you need to to
be able to operate already? And so, uh,
most most places that are really looking
at it have already gone through that
process. You know, have you had your
have you gotten your certificate of
occupancy as a business? Have you gone
through, you know, the fire inspection?
Like those kinds of things. So, there's
not really going to be a whole lot new.
Now, if someone wants to establish a new
center and they're opening that up, that
may take a little bit more time. But in
reality, the difference in the delay
between the training and education and
the equity fund and the locations
portion is really only going to be about
a month and a half to two months.
>> Okay. But what about patients?
>> Right. So, we're looking at December for
patients. And so, by that point, we'll
have healing centers. We'll have the
training will be set up. Excellent.
Because also remember once we have these
training rules in place because we've
talked previously about the reciprocity
with the other states people who've been
trained. So we will have those
individuals who are already trained um
and who will be able to go through this
and help those initial patients. It's
going to take time for the educational
programs to set up, get their students
in, do all of that. And so by the time
they have that, that's going to probably
take more than a month, month and a half
that we'll have the healing center set
up.
>> Excellent. Thank you.
>> Does that make s I mean I'm hoping sort
of laying that out as a timeline a
little bit helps.
>> Well, I also get that it can change, but
I just love what I'm hearing. So, thank
you.
Well, and it may adjust a little bit,
but know that our goal is that by the
beginning of December, all of these
rules will be in place, which doesn't,
by the way, mean that there won't be
changes. As we actually, you know, as as
the program implements, we're going to
get feedback from everybody saying,
"This part worked well, this part
didn't. Can you change this part of the
regulation? This is a little too
restrictive." Like for example, James,
we may end up finding that you're
completely right and that four just
isn't achievable for those groups and we
may have to adjust that or are there
other adjustments we need to make with
regard to that sort of thing. Um, and
looking at different possibilities.
We're we're not perfect. None of us are
ever going to be perfect. And as with
any new program, as it rolls out, we're
going to find that there's going to be
things we need to change a little bit.
Now, we'll take some time to evaluate
that. So don't anticipate that suddenly
we go oh we've seen three patients now
we need to change all these things in
January we'll take several months and
we'll look at it and see what's working
see what's not working and then we'll
look at doing uh essentially think of it
as like a cleanup rule making where we
make those additions those changes that
need to happen. There may be areas that
we completely miss. Even though we've
all been talking about this and looking
at it and we did this compilation, in
another three months, somebody may go,
you know, you know, oh wait, we
completely missed this entire large area
that we need to ensure that people are
getting trained on and we need to add
that on in. We'll have that ability to
do that um and through the regulations
and making a regulation change. So, just
always keep that in mind a little bit.
But yes, our goal is first patients to
be seen in December. Um, and I think
we're well on the way to do that.
Anyway, sorry. Now I'm on a soap box.
I'm still excited if you can't tell.
Uh, Greg, I'm sorry you've been patient
while I've been on my diet track.
>> No, I'm here for it. I like your
excitement. Um I also want to point out
that you are an ambitious
ambitious and well-calated individual
and uh this orchestration is massive and
I want to respect that. Um I wanted to
come back to the mentoring requirements
for a minute and just kind of like talk
through a user story so to make sense of
this. Um, the way I'm imagining what I'm
reading here is I complete a program and
that facility that trains me has adject
faculty outside of the course faculty
and those are people that I can self-
select to um engage in a mentoring
process. Um once I complete that that's
reported back to the training facility
for records and admin admin stuff one of
those admin things facility pays or
compensates that mentoring adjunct
practitioner for their time is that am I
hearing that right?
>> Yeah that is absolutely one model that
could be utilized for the mentoring. Um,
it would of course be up to that
educational program exactly how they
want to do that. Whether it's adjunct
faculty, faculty they have or even
potentially contracting with other
practitioners to be there to support
these new practitioners and
facilitators. The important part about
it is we want to ensure we you know
there's so many times in especially in
the helping professions where people
they graduate they finish an internship
or a practicum and then suddenly they're
just sort of out there and they're
trying to make those connections of for
support and for help. And if they run
into a situation, they may not feel
comfortable turning to their supervisor.
Like if they feel like maybe they made a
misstep, they may not feel comfortable
turning and talking to their direct
supervisor, they may want to talk to
someone else to get that bit of
mentoring and that other assistance. Um,
and then of course in like in that kind
of a case still the mentor hopefully
will still say you should still talk to
your supervisor, but that way they can
get some ideas on how to approach a
situation or how to handle it. And so
the idea is is to provide that support
after graduation. Um, and it's one of
the things that quite frankly, um,
throughout our higher education is one
of the areas that we hear from lots of
people all the time that, oh, my degree
was great and I learned a whole lot, but
I didn't feel like I had any support
when I went out into the workforce. And
so, what we're trying to really do here
is provide a little something to have
that support.
>> Yeah. And what one of the things that I
want to appreciate here is the self
similarity to the therapeutic process
and the um regeneration
and mirroring that I'm seeing in this
and I think that's super super valuable.
I think
I'll just let that slide. The one other
thing I wanted to touch on is the client
load for training facilities. And um I
mean this is maybe just a bucket like
how are we going to handle that? How are
we how are we recruiting and clearing
cuz that could be dozens. It could be
hundreds. It could like capacity is an
unknown at this point. So it's like if
we need all these people for group
sessions and individual sessions to go
through a cont a cohort of educators
like
that's massive. That could potentially
be massive. It is and that's a great
>> Oh, go ahead,
>> Greg.
>> And do we get to track those people as
participants in the program?
>> Yes. So that second part is yes. Uh the
first part as far as where is what we
envision will happen is the educational
programs will set up partnerships with
various healing centers in order to be
able to do this. And my hope would be,
I'll put this out publicly, but my hope
would be then is that patients who are
going through that training session get
a lower rate potentially um because they
are doing that in part with students who
are going through practicums.
But then that's just my wish. So
okay, and we have uh Katherine. Go on
ahead, Katherine.
>> So I want to kind of second that wish. I
actually would really love to be able to
offer low cost for the patients. Um
maybe even no cost sometimes. Um which
kind of leads me to the next question
then. What about this health equity
fund? Can any of that be used towards
helping pay for some of the trainings
and or for the patients coming through
the training programs? I'm just kind of
curious if there's any potential for
subsidies to help people with the costs.
Um because 120 hours, you know, I'm just
I I I think we all want to be able to
offer it as cheap as we possibly can. Um
but we have to pay people to do this
work, too. So, I'm just wondering if
there's any like subsidies at all or or
potentials.
That's my question. Thank you.
>> Sure. So, that's a great question,
Katherine, and it's one of the things uh
we haven't actually brought it to the
equity committee, but it's one of the
things that um we were talking a little
bit about here as well because of my
earlier comment of hopefully at a
reduced charge or reduced price is that
could potentially be one of the ways
that the equity fund could be utilized
where if someone is willing to go
through at one of the healing centers
during the sessions where students are
going through their practicums, that
that might either be able to be deferred
some of the costs deferred through the
equity fund or whether in part or in
full. And so then the healing center
would still get paid and the
practitioners and the all of that get
paid, but that it would be a reduced
price for the patients. And so this
might be a way to be able to do that.
Um, we're still looking into uh as far
as for uh the students themselves and
whether or not there might be a way to
utilize some of the equity funds for
that. Um, but that's a part of some of
those next questions. So, uh, I will use
this as a plug for Desba and the equity
committee that that is that is a great
place to come on in to talk about some
of those potential, uh, issues and
solutions.
I'm not sure is Despa on this today.
This this one I'm not sure if she was.
She was in the earlier. Oh, yeah. She
was earlier, but maybe not anymore.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think she had to hop up. Yeah,
but it's a great question, Katherine,
and and it's one that my hope is that
down the road we'll be able to do a
little bit more with regard to that.
Okay. Um so the next set that we have is
um is actually about the educational
recordkeeping.
Um and so this is really quite frankly
um this part is really just the
administrative side. And so it's really
that the program shall maintain records
that include all of their course
syllabi, the enrollment records
including name of student start and
completion date for students, exam
results, the pardon me uh dates,
locations, number of patients seen
during the practicum sessions for the
practitioner students um that the
facilitators uh that they supervise
during practicum also needs to be
recorded for example. Um and we will and
and by the way we have already got plans
on this that all of this will be online.
So it will be something that will be you
know that people will be able to log
into a system and once they are
registered they will be able to input
their information. The school will be
able or the educational program will be
able to enter the system and then it'll
be able to be available. Um and then of
course that uh because it will be for
the uh the department will have access
that those completion certificates will
be able to be uploaded into that portal.
Um and then that the educational program
shall provide current and foreign
students their records upon request and
that they'll provide the records. We
provide that they'll be maintained uh
under this rule and then sent to the
department upon request and then the
records maintained for 5 years. Now, one
of the things about this and why we want
to also do it in this way is we also
recognize that not everybody is always
well, we would love for everybody to
succeed right off the bat. There is a
possibility that not everybody will. We
may have lots of different educational
programs come in and the capacity for it
or the desire for it be a lot less than
the number of programs. And so with
that, we don't want students to run into
a situation where they then don't have
access to their graduation. you know,
their certificates of completion and all
of that. And that's a part of why we
want to ensure that those will get
uploaded to the department because then
while the department will not be the uh
the place of record, we at least can
then act as a backup for those programs
in case something were to happen. So if
say for example down the road and Greg,
I'm just going to pick on you since you
have your hand up. If Greg had completed
a program and then that program
unfortunately went out of business, Greg
could then turn around to the department
and say, "Hey, this is what I'd like,
but you know, XYZ consultants and
education services went out of business.
Can I get a copy of my certificate, you
actually already would have have access
to it through the online portal, but we
could help and arrange for that." So,
just to get
>> a student, I probably wouldn't have
completed anything
>> somehow. I doubt that, Greg. But Greg,
go on ahead.
>> Um, I just think it would be prudent to
include HIPPO uh compliance into into
this one.
>> That's actually a part of everything
that we do. Um, for example, when we do
contracts and everything, that's a part
of it. It actually bleeds over a little
bit. Oh, pardon me. I try usually not to
use those kinds of uh um uh illusions to
things and metaphors, but um it also
goes over into what also occurs for
students, which is furpa, which is
essentially HIPPA, but for students. And
so it also is the same sort of thing
that um organizations that are doing
education can't release grades, things
like that except under permission and
consent. And so there'll be all those
sort of things that'll be included in on
this such as you know the students have
to consent to certain things as well as
the educational institution or
organization. So great point on it Greg
but that's already that's already a
portion of what is required for any of
our kinds of online portals.
>> Yeah just universal coverage. Got it.
>> But it's a good point and it is
something that we need to make sure that
we do include uh with regard to it. So,
I'll add that because it's always
helpful.
James, go on ahead.
Just question on the recordkeeping part
here is it appears to me like this is
just the general recordkeeping
requirements for the program itself or
the students going through the program.
Is there any thought on adding something
with recordkeeping as far as the actual
program itself? Uh, i.e. per se. When
the board of uh when you guys show up
and you want to do an inspection,
there's going to be a bunch of records
that have to be kept. And there's really
nothing in this thing so far about that.
You know, we need to educate the the
centers as well as facilitators and the
practitioners on, you know, what kind of
inspectional things are they should be
expected as well as how to respond. I I
do see an issue a lot of times, guys, in
Oregon where people don't know how to
respond to complaints or issues that the
DO issues. If something comes up and you
have um per se, a you're one of these
people that that carries this
registration and and you get a complaint
on yourself. Um you know, how are you
going to address that complaint is very
important. Um and I think there needs to
be something where we we kind of teach
these people how to respond. I'm not
saying specifically how to respond DOM
or just something that that lets them
know, you know, that you're going to go
through this process and it could cost
you your registration if you don't do it
right. And so, um, just just thoughts on
that. Thank you.
>> Yeah. No, that's great, James. That's
actually I'm glad you brought it on up,
but that's actually a part of the New
Mexico module where we talk about the
act and the requirements uh, and you
know, how what all of the different
parts and pieces are going to need to
do. Now, we haven't done that portion of
the regulation yet um because we just
haven't gotten to that part yet and
we're focusing really on the education
piece, but that is a part of that. So,
thank you. I do appreciate that.
>> Greg,
I just think to James' point, um and it
might be something that's more like IP
for the training facilities like but to
offer business classes like how do I run
this? how do I survive this industry as
a business? Um, whereas that might not
be a DO requirement. I think that might
be something that people can consider
when they're setting up their programs.
>> You know, Greg, that's a great point and
it's one of those things as well that
again, these are the minimum
requirements for these different
permits. That doesn't mean that, for
example, somebody who is the best
practitioner in the world may be the
worst business person in the world. we
really would recommend that they also go
through those other kinds of training
courses which sometimes are quite a lot
more hours than we're even requiring
here. So, we did not want to put that on
in, but as part of the practices we're
going to be talking about if you plan on
managing or or uh opening up a healing
center, you really should probably go
through some business and legal classes.
So, that's a great point, but that also
is part of the um the uh approved
location section. So, yeah. Uh
Katherine,
>> so um I think this is also amazing. One
thing I'm wondering and it may be later
on the document. I don't know because I
keep that keeps happening. What are
going to be the requirements for the
people that are running practicums? like
I understand this is what we're looking
to roll out for, you know, everybody. I
know that there's going to be people
grandfathered in, but what are going to
be requirements to actually be able to
train and to do a practicum? Because,
like I said in in the last meeting, I
know a lot of programs out there that
you can grandfather in um that that you
can take a program and never have guided
a single person like they exist. So, are
we going to require anything around that
just to make sure that the people that
are running these these trainings have
some
have some experience?
>> So, Katherine, that's a great point.
When we reviewed some of the stuff on
the reciprocity, we had included in a
piece that they would have to
demonstrate that they actually do have
practice with patients. Um, and that if
they didn't, then they could potentially
go to one of the educational training
programs that that's set up to be able
to get some of that practice because,
for example,
>> somebody who just graduates, you know,
we're talking about this being ready in
December and we talked about the
reciprocity being available for maybe
about the first year or so, uh, that the
program is there, uh, or that the
program is implemented. So, what if you
have somebody who just finishes doing a
training in November up in Colorado, but
they didn't have a practicum piece?
Well, they could potentially come here
and work with one of the programs here
and do the practicum piece. Great.
>> So, that's a part of that. Um, and uh I
hope that's helpful. And as far as for
like requirements, it would be somebody
who has demonstrated like they are going
to need these educational programs are
going to need to submit an application
that includes who is their faculty? Do
the faculty have experience? Have they
been trained elsewhere? How have they
been trained? And be able to do all of
that. We're still working on some of
those pieces as far as exactly what they
are. My hope is by the next meeting we
have that part for you all.
>> Excellent. Excellent. I just want to
make sure we're we're paying attention
to that piece, too. Right. That Okay.
Thank you.
>> Yeah. No, no, it's a great question and
and I'm glad that it's been raised. Um,
we do only have a little bit of time
left and um I just have one little
section. So, I timed this about right um
for what I thought we would be able to
cover today. And this next piece um is
the continuing education requirement.
And so for this, we do have it broken
down a little bit differently. So that
uh we have the diagnostic clinicians
need to complete a minimum of 8 hours of
continuing medical education credits
specific to psychedelic medicine or
therapy every two years. And again,
remember the diagnostic clinician is not
usually going to be the practitioner or
any of that. If they are going to be a
practitioner, they'll have to go through
the practitioner training um just like
any other practitioner. Um and then for
practitioners and facilitators, we do
have that they would have to complete a
minimum of 20 hours of continuing ed
credits every two years. And then of
course and we will adjust this uh based
on some of the recommendations from
today uh keep current their basic life
support certification and uh in addition
to the 20 hours
and does this sound reasonable? And by
the way, my hope would be is that some
of these educational uh programs that
develop offer items that will be
continuing education as well. So they
could go into more depth into different
areas or as more research comes in, they
could focus on, you know, uh other
potentials uh whether it be uses for
psilocybin where it's beneficial in
other cases or therapy modalities or
just overall in general.
So, I just wanted to say something real
quick. So, um, right now we're we're
just getting this all down here. And so,
as far as education modules go, um, now
is the Department of Health looking at
um, how these modules will be put
together? Is that do you want us and our
committee to develop that or
>> No, it's really at this point honestly,
Brenda, it's really about does this look
good? Does this look like that framework
for the curricula? And then the
educational programs themselves set up
their specific curricula. They just have
to include all of these items. And we've
broken it out into these couple of
module sections from uh you know with
the exam sort of set in here. But again,
how they actually do each individual
course as they do their curricula is
really going to be up to their up to
those programs. But we think that this
actually flows fairly well.
>> Does that make sense?
>> And one Yeah. Yeah. One other thing I
wanted to say about um facilities uh
just going back a little bit that um
it's really important I've worked in a
lot of different facilities. It's really
important for facilities to have their
own oversight for audits. So um I I I
participated in a lot of the the kind of
audits and and I think you know uh part
of the education
uh too is prepare students for how um
and what does an audit look like as well
because that's part of the
administration thing and keeping records
correct and uh organized and uh up up to
you know snuff for all of this um that
we're doing. And so that you know if a
real let's say there's a really good um
uh clinic, however, uh their
recordkeeping and everything is a little
bit off and they get an audit and then
they go, "Oh, well, you know, you guys
can't keep running it things like this
because your paperwork is not done
correctly or done done in the in the
proper manner that it should be." So,
um, you know, I think having, um, you
know, an education piece on, yeah, on a
little bit of a little bit of business
could be thrown in there, too, just to
give an idea of, uh, you know, how
insurance works, um, you know, how the
lights stay on and, um, you know, what
safety protocols are there. So I a
little a little piece of that in the
education I think would be really good
because I think a lot of clinicians
don't know how facilitate how
facilitators how places work how clinics
work and that that's really um good
because if you have this um over uh over
if a if a clinician is like contracted
wants to work for a facility
that that they're not a good fit for.
They would need to know what the nuts
and bolts of their business and business
model is. So, I'm I just kind of wanted
to throw that in there because I have
had businesses and it it is auditing is
one of the scariest things, but I think
um learning a little bit about that and
how to handle it. And it also keeps a a
clinician in line too about how they're
keeping their records u uh up, you know,
uh up to the standards that meet the DO
in New Mexico.
So, um, what I'm I'm going to go ahead
and do is put into the New Mexico module
because I think that really fits in
under the documentation requirement
part. Um, but, um, I think maybe doing
that as, uh, having the audit sort of
specified a little bit more can be
helpful to make sure that something like
that is included. Um, uh, and, uh, have
that part there. So, hopefully that
helps.
And it looks like uh Daniel, it said,
"I'm hoping you'll accept transfers from
other international certified CPAT
courses." And I did uh I did throw a
recommendation in there in one of our
past um
uh meetings for incorporating like
people who've studied in the Netherlands
or Canada or Mexico. Um, and I'm, you
know, I think, you know, whether or not
the DO accepts that or not, it's really
up to the DO. Correct.
>> Well, part of it is going to be about
reviewing the curriculum. Um, part of
the reason why we can utilize Colorado
and Oregon uh programs that they've
accepted is because we can say those
have already been rude have already been
reviewed by United States governmental
agencies or uh governments overall. Um
and so we can do that otherwise what we
would have to do is the we would have to
actually evaluate what those other
courses are to be able to go through who
is actually for example accredited them
and all of that. Now that may be a
possibility down the road for this
initial portion. I think that quite
frankly that would be too much of a
burden for the DO to be able to do.
Okay. So we've got a couple of hands up.
So, uh, first one, James.
>> Hey, Don. Back on the continuing
education section. Thoughts on, uh, just
expansion here on, you know, when you're
talking about medical
uh, right there it says, um, using u
medical
continuing education, education credits.
those C CE CEC's it's are we discussing
um you know here again being very broad
because we're going to have a bunch of
different type of medical professionals
or others um you know and in all these
different fields everything's called
different educ you know continue
education CME CUS uh CPEs um you know
social workers use ACCE are we saying
specifically and again I want to be kind
of broad um saying that that is
including all of those type of
continuing education credits. I just
want to make sure that we're gonna
>> it's it's kind of broad there. I just
want to make sure do we need to be more
specific or we just keep it broad and
say it's up to you as an individual. And
then second question is does the you
know when we're treating these different
disease states i.e. um you know end of
life i.e. PTSD is there need to be any
specific CES requirements for those
specific requirements? It's just a
thought. Doesn't have to be right now.
It could be something the do goes into.
Uh but you know, breaking it down into,
hey, I want you to have eight of what
you're specifically specialized in or,
you know, just thoughts on that guys.
Thanks.
>> Yeah, not a not a problem at all, James.
And you'll actually notice we did
actually specify for the diagnostic
clinicians that they need to be CMEs
because we want to really ensure that at
that level that individuals that they
are going through that medical education
that is specific for the medical side.
But for practitioners and facilitators,
we really did leave it open-ended on
purpose because we do know they're
called different things with different
professions. And so it really is on that
for continuing education. We really want
to ensure that people are able to do it
and there are a lot of programs out
there that offer both CMEs and CEUs that
are specific towards psychedelics. So,
we really want to ensure that that's
there. Um, yeah.
>> Also, Don, one more question. Sorry. Are
we looking at a two-year renewal? I'm
just assuming that because it says every
two years. Is that what you guys are
shooting for? Is two years?
>> Yes, that's correct.
Okay, Greg.
>> Um, I think most of what my questions
already got handled. Um,
>> okay.
>> But I do think that um
the definition of like it like this is
probably future work, but defining how
those CEU
programs get qualified, right? Um I know
that um Dr. Fi Feti is doing a course in
ethics and decision-m and navigating the
professional boundaries and psychedelic
landscape at Southwestern like next
month or something like that. we're
pre-program or whatever, but like
something like that sounds like an
excellent opportunity, but it's like
does the institution
say so is s would in this instance would
Southwestern be approved training
facility for the DO? Not them
specifically, but for example, because
we want to stay out of specifics. And
then are all of their programs covered
or is if there's a program at a
different institution can individual
programs be qualified as CEU credits?
>> Uh so for no no it's a great question
Greg and it sort of does dovetail into
what James was saying is for for an
institution or a course for example to
get CME or CEUs they do have to go
through a certification process and an
approval process. excuse me, an approval
process. And so they would still have to
make that. So part of the definition
when we do put that in for CEUs is
they'll have to be essentially from a
recognized accrediting agency or
organization. And we'll make sure to
have that in that definition. Um, but we
want to keep it broad so that depending
upon which field and what area they are,
they will be able to be accepted so long
as they've gone through that kind of a
review process. And we have quite a few
people who have been involved in this
process here and in other ways who
actually are very familiar with those.
um you know uh even here with the do for
example we have a lot of trainings where
we actually offer CME and CEUs and so
going through that accreditation process
while it can be a little bit of little
time consuming it's actually not that
difficult to do usually involves doing
things such as um submitting the CVs or
resumes of the the uh instructors
includes um you know having a curricula
actually outlined initially um And
really most of the time that's about it.
Some of the organizations do require
fees, some do not. So that will just
depend. And that's why sometimes CMEs
and C use are so expensive for people.
And it's why it's great when someone's
already going to a conference and
they're already offering CMEs or CUS as
a part of their conference. Sometimes
that alone paying the conference fee is
worthwhile just to get those continuing
ad credits.
>> And I see Brenda's nodding. Yes.
>> Yeah. like like if if people could top
up at psychedelic science or something
that would be great.
>> Um
>> yeah, it sounds like for first iteration
approved training facilities hosting
pro programs seems like the the most
logical progression.
>> Right. And by the way, we are looking
into department of health doing certain
things. Like for example, we work
currently, not not our program
specifically, but some of the other
programs work with um AIDS education and
training center out of UN M um and offer
for the conference they do and for some
of the trainings offer CMEs and CEUs
through that and those are usually free
of charge for example. So we want to be
able to do some things like that and
offer some credits and CEUs. um some of
the project echo courses also offer them
through similar process. So we're
looking at as we develop the program
having those kinds of abilities as well
because we also want to try to ensure to
help keep costs lower for people and so
if we as a department can even offer
some CMEs and CUS then that would also
be beneficial but that's down the road a
little bit.
Okay. I thought I saw another hand up,
but I'm not sure who it was. If there
was somebody who had another question,
>> Ian, it was Ian. I think he lowered it.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> He answered my question.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Okay, great.
>> Well, we only have a couple minutes
left. So, anybody have any final
thoughts or ideas?
>> Otherwise, what we're going to do is
from a program standpoint is we're going
to start converting this on over into
the full regulatory language. And so,
um, we'll kind of go from there. But
Brenda, what I would ask is if you're
okay, could we get consent from
everybody here to bring this to the
overall board?
>> Yes, of course. So, anyone who um uh is
in favor of what we have established
right now, uh please raise your hand.
Okay. So, we have six people. Anyone
else?
Okay. So, it looks like we um anyone who
is uh objecting, lower your hand.
>> Well, first let's
>> Oh, wait. Wait a minute. Did I put that
backwards?
>> Yeah, that's okay. We'll we'll have if
everybody will lower their hand.
Perfect. Okay. Go ahead, Brenda.
>> Okay. Uh so uh anyone have any
objections to what we have written here
so far?
Okay. Kate
>> Kate, is there something we can do to
improve it? What do And if you don't
want to talk right now, that's fine.
>> No, I'm happy to talk. I was actually
just wanting to say something before
voting, but u you know, I appreciate how
quickly we're moving and there's a lot
here. So, I was hoping we'd get a copy
to take a look at and just digest a
little bit. Um but, you know, I'm not
going to say anything if everybody else
is feeling good about moving ahead.
>> No. And and remember, Kate, we'll we
will we will be posting it to the
website. We will be doing all of that.
And there will be lots of other you know
as you review it especially we do have
you know during the the process even
after the board has gone through we'll
still also have the um you know the
regulation hearings themselves and so
people will be able to make comments. So
if we miss something and as as we've
done with this last set, there were
changes that we made after the rule
hearing, you know, that went into it and
now we'll see if they make into the
final. Um but um it's not this is not
the end of the process. This is in many
ways sort of as Brenda was saying, this
is kind of the middle of it for this
part and we have a lot more still to do
on this. You know, there's not there's
other sections. So we will have other
pieces that we'll be adding.
>> Right. I I hear you and I really
appreciate the process. I'm going to be
meeting with someone at Brain Futures
and they've been analyzing over a dozen
programs. Would it be all right to share
these uh what we have here just to get
some feedback?
>> Yeah, that's perfectly fine. Kate, we've
actually talked with Brand Futures quite
a bit ourselves.
>> Cool. I I look I know you've done a lot
and it looks great and I'm just, you
know, I I had tech problems so I missed
some of this. I'm just trying to catch
my breath. So, thank you so much.
>> No, thank you, Kate. We appreciate it.
>> Oh, absolutely. Thank you. Thank Thank
you everyone for uh participating in
this. We couldn't do it without anybody.
I mean, we really needed to go over all
of this with a fine tooth comb so we're
not missing anything. And of course,
like Dominic said, we're in the middle.
And so if things need to be tweaked or
changed, um I think going forward right
now is um uh absolutely what um we've
combed through everything. So um so if
that is an agreement um let's go ahead
and uh go forward with this document.
Dominic um you feel comfortable with
that?
>> Great. Thank you. Um, and then I guess
uh the only other question I have and I
just wanted to bring up before we set
the next meeting date is um the next
board meeting is actually on the 26th
um and uh which is two weeks from today.
And I was wondering if it is possible
um to be able to do this to do the next
meeting prior to that maybe either on
the 24th or the 25th. Um, and the main
reason why is because then we can take
the cleanup that we've done on all of
this and maybe a few other little
sections to add on in that we've
discussed during today's meeting and
have that available as well then for the
board.
>> Okay. So, um, you're looking at the 24th
and the 25th of June
uh, for another education and training
meeting. Is that what you're saying?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Let me see. Um,
>> and so that's the Wednesday and Thursday
in two weeks.
>> Okay. Uh, let me just check my calendar
here real quick.
>> And just as a note, if we cannot, that's
perfectly fine as well.
>> I was just offering it as a potential
suggestion just because of the next
board meeting.
>> Okay.
I if it's if it's easier for everybody
here, then we can stay with the twoe
time frame and which would then be on
the 26th at 1:00.
I'm just checking my calendar here real
quick.
Um so that would be the 24th, the 25th.
Okay.
And we do, it does look like uh the 24th
doesn't work for several people,
>> right?
>> Uh but the 25th might be. So, and and
again, if the 25th does not, we're
perfectly fine with keeping it on Friday
the 26th. We just don't want to, you
know, that's not a problem.
>> Um
uh yeah, there's a there is a
possibility I could do, um what time on
uh 1 to 3 or in the morning? I I would
say that would be up to you if uh 1 to
three works. What would 1 to three on
the 25th work for other people?
Katherine says it would be perfect.
>> Okay. In the afternoon,
>> Greg, you have your hand up. Is that
okay? Okay. So,
>> yeah, absolutely. For me, like, don't
worry about my schedule. I just wanted
to clarify do does the department need
the revisions to be reviewed by
committee before they go to draft for
rules interpretation
or like what's the alignment with the
committee proposal? Do does it need to
go through the advisory board before it
goes to rules?
>> Uh not fully. um because we'll make
adjustments to what we do as far as
rules, but we do want the advisory board
to have their recommendations and
comments on it prior to us going to that
to that final rule portion. Um and um
and it doesn't need to necessarily come
through here again. I just thought some
of the other pieces that we've talked
about today, like some of the things
that Katherine's brought up and James
has brought up and you've brought up,
Greg, that we might be able to have
those ready for everybody to review. And
if we do that before the meeting on the
the board meeting on the 26th then we
would be able to um you know just move
that forward as well to the board itself
for consideration.
>> I think that in I in the effort of
efficiency I think that's a really good
idea but I think we could forego if
needed to make sure that it gets into
the advisory board meeting.
>> Yeah.
So okay well but it looks like the 25th
does work for most people. Oh, it does
look like Kate cannot make the afternoon
of the 25th. So, if uh would keeping it
on the 26 from 1 to 3 work for everybody
involved who's here right now because
again I we would rather have people be
here than push it by that day or two.
I I could I could make it the the the
26th of course, but um see the 24 25th.
Um I can always move my schedule around.
That's not a problem.
>> Well, and Katherine's saying she can't
meet on the 26th. So,
>> okay.
>> Are we okay with continuing on the 25th
then? And we would do 25th from 1 to 3.
>> I'm okay with that.
>> It looks otherwise like that will be
good. Sorry about that, Kate. Um, but
okay. So, we'll go forward with the
25th. And I had put it in the chat, but
just to make sure everybody knows is we
will send this on out. Not only do we
put it out on the website, but for
everybody who's registered here in this
meeting. Um, it may not be this
afternoon, but on Monday, we'll make
sure to get it this document that we
reviewed today sent out to everyone uh
through the email for people who are
registered.
>> Perfect. And um there are some other
meetings coming up. Um there's Ian's on
the 15th on Monday, June 15th. Um and
then uh Desba has one on the 21 23rd
from 3 to 5. So Ian's is at 9 and 10 on
the 15th, right?
>> And uh June 23rd is uh from 3 to 5 for
Desbuck.
>> Yes. And and as always, you can always
see and register uh for future meetings
on the advisory board website.
Okay. All right. Oh, and thank you,
Johnny. You beat me to it. Johnny just
put in the chat the link for the
advisory board website, so for for the
other meetings.
Okay.
Well, thank you everybody.
>> Yeah, I guess we'll adjourn.
>> Yeah, I I just I really appreciate
everybody and the feedback. This was
phenomenal today. I thank you Brenda for
the opportunity and uh I just and really
for again I just want to express all the
work that really has gone into it. I
know seeing this in sort of this
outline, it really is the culmination of
all of the things that people have been
doing over the last several months, the
documents that have been submitted and
sent to us. And I think that you all can
see we've really taken it very seriously
and looking at it and trying to figure
out the best ways to really be able to
do this in a way that's going to be
beneficial for everybody and uh and
create a really great program. So I just
thank you all for all the work that
you've been doing. Thank you.
>> And thank you again for me too. I'm glad
that all of you guys came here and um
gave your input. This is um we could
like I always say we can't do it without
you and your participation, your
comments and your feedback and your
ideas. Uh you it everyone is making this
into a uh superb program. So thank you.
>> Have a great Friday and weekend
everyone.